sortedfood.com 2019-04-10

# Privacy Policy | Sorted

**Effective Date: May 25, 2018**

Sorted (“Sorted”, “we”, “us” or “our”) respects your right to privacy. Our Privacy Policy explains how we and some of the companies we work with collect, use, share and protect information in relation to our mobile services, website, and any software provided on or in connection with Sorted services (collectively, the “Service”), and your choices about the collection and use of your information.

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your personal information, then please contact us using the contact details at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

**What does Sorted do?**

Sorted is a business that enables you to access food and cooking-related digital entertainment, experiences, recipe ideas, cookbooks and merchandise through our website, our events, or by joining the Sorted Membership. You can also share your own comments in our forums on the website and submit your own recipe suggestions (collectively the “Services”). By using our Service we are providing a platform for you to post comments, including recipes, photos and other materials (“User Content”), to the Service and to share User Content publicly. This means that other Users may search for, see, use, or share any of your User Content that you make publicly available through the Service.

For more information about Sorted please see the [About Us](https://sorted.club/about-us/) section of our Website.

Our Privacy Policy applies to all visitors, users, and others who access the Service (“Users”).

**Legal basis for processing personal information**

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. 

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only (i) where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, (ii) where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights, or (iii) where we have your consent to do so.  In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). 

If we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are. Our legitimate interests include the operation of our platform and communicating with you as necessary to provide our services to you and for our legitimate commercial interest, for instance, when responding to your queries, improving our platform, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities. 

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below.

**1\. WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE COLLECT IT**

We collect the following types of information:

**Information you provide us directly:**

Your username, password and e-mail address when you register for a Sorted account. Profile information that you provide for your user profile (e.g., first and last name, photo, biographical description, gender, location). 

User Content that you post to the Service.

Product and service orders you place via the Service, including your payment method and associated delivery and payment addresses.

Communications between you and Sorted.

**Analytics information:**

We may use third-party analytics tools to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service. These tools collect information sent by your device or our Service, including the web pages or screens you visit, and other information that assists us in improving the Service. We combine this information with analytics information from other Users so that it cannot reasonably be used to identify any particular individual User.

**Cookies and similar technologies:**

When you visit the Service, we may use cookies, similar technologies and local storage to collect information about how you use Sorted and provide features to you.

We may enable advertisers or other partners to serve ads or services to your devices, which may use cookies or similar technologies placed by us or the third party.

More information is available in our [Cookies Policy](https://sorted.club/cookies/) section.

**Information that we collect automatically:**

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you make a request to access (i.e., visit) a web page. It can also be provided when the content of the webpage is downloaded to your browser or device.

When you use our Service, our servers automatically record certain log file information, including your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. We may also collect similar information from emails sent to our Users which then help us track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of the Service.

Unique application numbers: when you install or uninstall Services containing a unique application number, or when such a Service searches for automatic updates, that number and information about your installation, for example the type of operating system, may be sent to us.

**Device identifiers:**

When you use a mobile device like a tablet or phone to access our Service, we may access, collect, monitor, store on your device, and/or remotely store one or more “device identifiers.” Device identifiers are small data files or similar data structures stored on or associated with your mobile device, which uniquely identify your mobile device. A device identifier may be data stored in connection with the device hardware, data stored in connection with the device’s operating system or other software, or data sent to the device by Sorted.

A device identifier may deliver information to us or to a third party partner about how you browse and use the Service and may help us or others to provide reports or personalised content and ads. Some features of the Service may not function properly if use or availability of device identifiers is impaired or disabled.

**Metadata:**

Metadata is usually technical data that is associated with User Content. For example, Metadata can describe how, when and by whom a piece of User Content was collected and how that content is formatted.

**2\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

In addition to some of the specific uses of information we describe in this Privacy Policy, we may use information that we receive to:

  * help you efficiently access your information after you sign in
  * remember information so you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Service;
  * provide personalised content and information to you and others, which could include recommended recipes, products, services, or online ads and other forms of marketing
  * provide, improve, test, and monitor the effectiveness of our Service
  * develop and test new products and features
  * monitor metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns
  * diagnose or fix technology problems

**3\. SHARING YOUR INFORMATION**

We will not sell or otherwise transfer your information to third parties outside Sorted (or the group of companies of which Sorted is a part) without your consent, except as noted in this Privacy Policy.

**Parties with whom we may share your information:**

We may share User Content and your information (including but not limited to, information from cookies, log files, device identifiers, location data, and usage data) with businesses that are legally part of the same group of companies that Sorted is part of, or that become part of that group (“Affiliates”). Affiliates may use this information to help provide, understand, and improve the Service (including by providing analytics) and Affiliates’ own services (including by providing you with better and more relevant experiences).

We also may share your information as well as information from tools like cookies, log files, and device identifiers and location data, with third-party organisations that help us provide the Service to you (“Service Providers”). Our Service Providers will be given access to your information as is reasonably necessary to provide the Service under reasonable confidentiality terms. A list of our current Service Providers is available [here.](https://sorted.club/sorteds-service-providers/)

We may also share certain information such as cookie data with third-party advertising partners. This information would allow third-party ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you.

We may remove parts of data that can identify you and share anonymised data with other parties. We may also combine your information with other information in a way that it is no longer associated with you and share that aggregated information.

**Parties with whom you may choose to share your User Content:**

Please be aware that any information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service, such as User Content, becomes available to the public. Once you have shared User Content or made it public, that User Content may be re-shared by others.

Any User Content that you make public is searchable by other Users.

If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service.

**What happens in the event of a change of control:**

We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets; or if Sorted or substantially all of it’s assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held about its customers will be one of the transferred assets. However you will continue to own your user content and any buyer will honour the commitments made in this Privacy Policy.

**Responding to legal requests and preventing harm:**

We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to do so in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation or request; to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements or to investigate potential breaches; or to protect your vital interests or the rights, property or safety of Sorted (which includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction).

**4\. HOW WE STORE YOUR INFORMATION**

**Storage and Processing:**

Your personal information may be transferred to, and processed in countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA), including countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country and in some cases may not be as protective.

Specifically, our website servers are located in Ireland and our Affiliates and Service Providers operate around the world. This means that when we collect your personal information we may process it in any of these countries. We may need to transfer information in this way to carry out our contract with you, to fulfil a legal obligation, to protect the public interest and/or for your or our legitimate interests.

However we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**How does Sorted keep my personal information secure?**

We use appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect the personal information that we collect and process about you and provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information, for example requesting a unique password to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. However, Sorted cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to Sorted or guarantee that information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed.

Please do your part to help us. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to emails between you and Sorted, at all times. 

**5\. YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION**

When you register for your account with us you can also tell us whether you wish us to use your personal data to contact you by means of email notifications. You can unsubscribe from these at any point by the link at the bottom of every email.

We may contact you by email from time to time with information on products or services available from Sorted or complementary products or services from our commercial partners that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of marketing communications by the link available at the bottom of every email.

We may send you Service-related emails (e.g., account verification, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices). Please note that you may not opt out of Service-related e-mails.

**Your account information and profile/privacy settings:**

Update your account at any time by logging in and changing your account settings.

Unsubscribe from email communications from us by clicking on the “unsubscribe link” provided in such communications. As noted above, you may not opt out of Service-related communications (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices).

**How long we keep your User Content:**

Following termination or deactivation of your account, Sorted, its Affiliates, or its Service Providers will retain information (including your profile information) and User Content where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, for audit purposes).

Where we have no ongoing legitimate need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example because your personal information has been stored in back up archives) then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

To delete your Sorted account, login and select the ‘delete’ option in your account settings.

**Your data protection rights:**

You have the following data protection rights:

  * If you wish to **access, correct , update or request deletion** of your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us using the contact details under the “How to contact us” heading below. 
  * In addition you can **object to processing** of your personal information, ask us to **restrict processing** of your personal information or **request portability** of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact details under the “How to contact us” heading below. 
  * You have the right to **opt-out of marketing communications** we send you at any time.  You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing e-mails we send you.  To opt-out of other forms of marketing (such as postal marketing or telemarketing), then please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below.
  * Similarly, if we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can **withdraw your consent** at any time.  Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the **right to complain to a data protection authority** about our collection and use of your personal information.  For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. 

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

**6\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

Sorted does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register for the Service. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us immediately at [club@sortedfood.com](mailto:club@sortedfood.com).

**7\. OTHER WEBSITES AND SERVICES**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by any websites or services linked to or from our Service, including the information or content contained within them. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Service to another website or service, our Privacy Policy does not apply to those third-party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website or service, including those that have a link on our website, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites or use these services. Please note that we are not responsible and do not have control over any third parties that you authorise to access your User Content. If you are using a third-party website or service and you allow them to access your User Content you do so at your own risk.

**8\. HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the Service, please contact us using the following details: Email: club@sortedfood.com

In the event of the death of a Sorted User, please contact us. We will usually conduct our communication via email; should we require any other information, we will contact you at the email address you have provided in your request. Email: [club@sortedfood.com](mailto:club@sortedfood.com)

The data controller of your personal information is Sorted Ventures Ltd, registered office at Stag House, Old London Road, Hertford SG13 7LA, United Kingdom.

**9\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time in response to changing legal, technical or business developments. When we do this, we will take appropriate measures to inform you, consistent with the significance of the changes that we make. We will obtain your consent to any material Privacy Policy changes if and where this is required by applicable data protection laws.

You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the “last updated” date displayed at the top of the Privacy Policy.
